See you next time.
The Tragedy of Ohara.
The Terror of the Buster Car.
Is that so?
Yes.
The evidence is clear.
This calls for nothing short of the death penalty.
We're waiting for your order.
It's unfortunate.
Seeing as they've broken the law so blatantly, there's really no other option.
We must enforce our own rules.
We don't need your mock sympathy, Elder Stars.
Save your breath.
You're talking to the leaders of the world, you damn criminal.
Show some respect.
That must be Professor Clover, Ohara's foremost authority on archaeology.
I'm familiar with your work.
You've contributed much to the world's cultural heritage.
It's sad to see a man of your intellect go astray.
The history of this planet belongs to all of mankind.
No matter what that history may be, you don't have the right to forbid us from learning it.
No one does.
Professor.
If one can read the Poneglyphs, then it's also possible that they can revive the ancient weapons and place the world in serious peril.
Even if you have the best of intentions, someone else could come along and use your research for evil.
Be it good or bad, mankind has the responsibility to accept whatever their history may hold.
As long as we don't succumb to fear and ignorance, we will be prepared for anything that may come.
That's idealistic.
Is it? Or are you just making convenient excuses to suit your needs?
In truth, there are two mysteries left unsolved.
Of course we want to read the Poneglyphs, but the reason why they were made in the first place is interesting as well.
Why was their message so important that they had to inscribe it on unbreakable stone to pass on to future generations?
Why were they hidden and scattered across the world?
Why were they not stored in a library?
The only logical conclusion is that they feared their message would be too easily destroyed if they had written it on paper.
In other words, they had an enemy.
Someone who was afraid of the information they wanted to pass on.
What are you trying to imply, Professor Clover?
Since the ancients have disappeared, we must assume that they were defeated by this enemy, and that whoever they were, they survived through history.
It may be no coincidence that roughly 800 years in the past, when the blank century came to an end, the organization we now call the World Government was founded.
Therefore, if this unknown enemy was indeed the World Government, it might be in their best interest to erase this inconvenient piece of information and let the ancients disappear into a fabricated blank century.
By analyzing ancient manuscripts and piecing together what we could from the few poneglyphs we were able to find, we discovered the existence of a previously unknown country.
Although the details we found were a bit scarce, we believe it was a grand and powerful kingdom.
And yet, despite their strength, not a trace remains, or rather, those traces were deliberately erased.
But they were prepared for this possibility, even as they faced the threat of extinction.
And so they etched their history in stone, before their kingdom was crushed under the might of the Allied Nations, now known as the World Government.
Thus, the reason why the poneglyphs were made becomes quite clear.
I see. That's a bold hypothesis.
It's true that the ancient weapons would be a threat to the world.
But more so than weapons, what I believe the World Government is afraid of is the history surrounding this lost kingdom.
Its existence and its ideologies are so dangerous to you that you would kill to keep them secret.
Although we still don't know what makes you fear this kingdom, we do at least know its name.
Since we've gone so far already, perhaps you'd like me to share it with you now.
Kill him!
Professor!
You left us no choice.
How dare you!
No, Professor!
Ohara knows too much.
You may give the order to attack.
Or don't move an inch!
No!
You mustn't let anyone escape!
Now then, with a golden transponder snail entrusted to me by Admiral Sengoku...
Professor!
Robin!
You fool!
I told you to run!
Hurry!
I invoked the buster call!
And that's a wrap!
He pressed something!
What is that?
Get out of here!
Go!
No!
I don't want to be alone!
You have to stop being so selfish!
This isn't the time!
Robin!
It's the buster call!
All battleships to your positions!
Prepare to open fire!
Fire!
What?
Hey!
Look!
The Tree of Knowledge is on fire!
Dammit!
What are you doing?
Are you insane?
Isn't it enough to take our lives?
Hey, it's not my fault.
Must have caught fire when they bombed your secret basement.
Stop this!
Right now!
You can't replace the documents in there!
Don't you realize that?
You!
Don't move!
Whoa!
We don't need guns anymore.
Time for the government agents to pull out.
Protect the books!
Let's put out the fire!
Hurry!
Pass the water over here!
Carry as many books outside as you can!
Bring that woman with you.
Get up!
There's still some info we have to wring out of her.
She can't die yet.
Just make sure she doesn't escape again.
acompañ in there!
Mami!
Please, Robin,
run while you still can.
You can't die here.
Not like this.
Mami, no!
Go! We're done for. There's no point in staying.
Robin!
Robin, don't!
You're my mother, aren't you?
Make up your mind, Olvia. Are you going to board this ship or not?
Mommy!
I'm holding her back! Just hurry and get on!
Mommy! Mommy! No! Mommy!
I'm sorry, Robin. I can never call myself your mother again.
After all these years, after all I've done, I don't have the right anymore.
Monster!
She's so scary! Her mom ran away!
Hey! That's my daughter's dress! You take it off!
I'm sorry, Aunt Roji. I just wanted to try it on.
You sure eat a lot for a freeloader.
Please answer me!
Are you my mom?
Hold on. That girl your daughter or what?
No.
Olvia!
I'm sorry, little girl.
You must be confusing me with someone else.
Even if it comes to this, I don't want you to be the daughter of a criminal.
Olvia!
Huh. What a weird little brat.
Right. Let's go.
It's me! It's Robin!
I've grown since the last time!
So maybe you don't recognize me!
I've been waiting for you all these years!
Are you sure?
You're really...
Not my mom!
Help me!
Just once!
Someday...
I wanted to hold your hand...
And walk together like a family!
I studied hard!
To become an archaeologist!
So I could go to sea with you!
I could read the Pornoglyphs too!
What did she say?
Robin! No!
So please, look at me!
Let me stay with you!
Mom!
Robin!
I've waited so long!
We're finally together!
Don't leave me alone again!
Moon again!
Oh no! Now what's going on?
Now commencing the buster call.
All ships fire at once.
Everything on the island of Ohara is your target.
Let nothing remain!
The research conducted here was far more extensive than we anticipated.
Make sure that knowledge is not passed on.
Do not allow it to leave the island.
Annihilate the devils of Ohara!
Turn it to the ground!
In the name of justice!
Damn it!
What the hell?
Can't you wait till we leave the island?
They're gonna kill us!
Stop it!
The Tree of Knowledge took a direct hit!
They're using their highest power against us.
They staged their investigation, but they were planning this from the start.
Bastards!
Hey, Chief.
That girl said she can read the Poneglyps.
Yeah.
She did, didn't she?
I don't know if it's true or not, though.
Probably safer to wipe her out just in case.
Don't let her leave the island.
Remember her face, alright?
We're retreating.
Then I'll grab Olvia.
Screw it!
The situation has changed!
Just run!
I'm not gonna get blown up trying to follow some stupid order!
Our number one priority is keeping me alive!
Retreat!
Everyone back to the ship!
Put out the fire on that side before it spreads!
Protect the library at all costs!
I've been waiting a long time to do this!
I'm glad!
Robin!
Mommy!
Robin, forgive me.
Please!
This is my fault for not watching over you with more care!
Is it really true that you can read the Poneglyphs?
I had to learn, since I wanted to be a scholar!
I never knew my little girl was an archaeologist.
That's amazing!
You must have studied hard while I was gone, huh?
These aren't things that just anyone can do.
I'm so proud!
Fortunately, the only ones who know about this are the officials who were here earlier.
We can't afford to waste any more time!
Olvia!
Take Robin and run!
If you can sneak her onto the evacuation ship, she might still be able to leave the island!
Robin!
I've been looking all over for you!
It's Saul!
So you met with your mother after all!
Saul!
Why in the world are you here?
Guess it must be fate!
I just happened to wash up here, and your little girl was the one who found me!
Anyhow, we ain't got time to chat right now!
You gotta get off this island!
I'll be fine, but I need you to take care of Robin for me, please!
But why? What about you? Are you going to come with me?
Are you going to come with me?
Olvia, are you?
I can't leave yet. There's something left to do.
No, Mom! You can't leave me now!
I'll stay here with you! I don't want to lose you again!
Robin, if you're a scholar of Ohara, you should know that history is mankind's greatest treasure.
Now that it's been passed on, it will illuminate the path to your future.
However, you must pass it on as well, or its light will disappear with the next generation.
Share those books! I'll take these!
We weren't trying to uncover some dark secrets.
We simply wanted to hear the voices of the past and protect them.
Unfortunately, our research ends here, but time marches on, even if Ohara is destroyed.
And as surely as we believe in the past, we believe in the future that you will inherit.
What does that mean?
Someday, you'll know.
Hurry! Take her and go, Saul!
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Stop it! I want to stay with you! Mommy! No!
I was happy to hear you call me that again.
Thank you. From now on, for my sake as well.
You must live, Robin!
Oh, Robin!
Vice Admiral Kuzan!
What now?
It looks like...
No, wait, it's gotta be!
So are you gonna tell me or not?
Spit it out already, man!
It's the deserter!
Vice Admiral Saul!
Please don't!
You have to take me!
I'll see you next time.